[gasps]
[Knuckle] No way.
Where could he have gone
in that condition?
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
[Shaiapouf] Will he do it,
abandon his original intent
and commit to an answer
without evidence?
[grunts]
[Shaiapouf chuckles]
He won't.
[Shaiapouf] I see
you've made your choice.
[Morel] Once I thought about it,
it was simple.
Your pupa appeared
after I played my card.
Since you only hid
after learning my agenda,
I knew that was your ability
and that it was a trap.
And the fact
that you didn't respond
when I lifted up my pipe
to strike you confirmed it.
In fact, you showed no signs
of reacting at all.
Didn't make any sense.
[Shaiapouf laughs]
[Morel gasps]
Fifteen minutes.
[chuckles]
That was how long
I expected you to take
I fully intended
to slip through the smoke
and move about the area freely.
I decided to take advantage
of that misconception
and quietly dispose of your friends.
So you thought I'd wait that long
in front of an empty husk?
Well, if that's how
he slipped through Smoky Jail,
I would never have
been able to see a thing.
[gasps]
[Shaiapouf] You should
have waited longer,
because my strategy to slip through
was a last resort.
But if I'm being perfectly honest,
I was quite upset about being trapped.
That's a crap diversion, and you're lying!
You made it through the smoke just fine.
[Shaiapouf] Well, true.
At that point,
that was all there was to it.
-[laughter continues]
-I was convinced
But you made some wild guesses
and removed the barrier.
-Thank you.
Smoke Troopers, Deep Purple!
[laughing]
[Morel] I can't destroy them?
They just divide and reassemble.
Are they invincible?
[laughing continues]
[together] Thank you! Bye-bye!
[Morel] Don't be fooled.
He's playing mind games.
My decision to attack
was the best option at the time.
No, I'm already playing into his hands
by dwelling on the past.
If I'm gonna win this,
I've got to anticipate his next moves.
To join up with the rest
of the Royal Guard,
to find and eliminate my companions,
and to reunite with the King.
That must be it.
His goals are the same as mine.
No problem.
Huh?
[dramatic music playing]
[groans]
[laughs]
[Morel] He got me.
I can't use any other moves.
If I deactivate Deep Purple,
I'll be defenseless.
[Menthuthuyoupi] Hey, are you the one…
who can teleport?
[gasps]
[guitar music playing]
Hmm?
What in the hell
did you do with Shoot, huh?
What's that?
Hmm?
[Morel] Eighty-nine Deep Purple puppets,
the most I can produce right now.
I'll use them to help Knuckle
as best I can.
I'll take your life!
[door creaks]
Okay. There's no one here.
Good. Time to escape, so let's go.
Damn it. They told us
we were gonna be safe here.
It's too bad
I can't get in touch with Sir Leol.
Oh, I know!
I can make you my deputy.
How's that sound?
[man] Help me.
Huh?
Please help me.
Get me out of here!
I need help.
You don't look so good, Director Bizeff.
No, I… can't move my legs.
Hmm?
Hmm.
If you do, I'm gonna die!
Yeah, no can do.
There's no way I can move all that stuff.
At the very least, call someone to help!
I told you no already!
I'm trying to get out of here A.S.A.P.
My boss is missing,
I have no direct line to the King,
Just tell me what you want!
There are mountains of treasure
in the basement!
so please, please pull me out!
[Hina] Where in the basement?
[Bizeff] There's a private area
reserved for the leader
that's located just beyond the shelter.
I'm in charge of the vault.
I'm the only one who has access.
[groaning]
You'll give me anything?
Oh, my.
You'd better keep your promise,
or I'm gonna kill you, okay?
[singing] ♪ Treasure, treasure ♪
♪ We're off
To find some treasure ♪
♪ Some pretty golden treasure… ♪
[Bizeff] This country
is absolutely done for.
I wasn't certain before,
but an air raid without my consultation
is all the proof I need.
I'm sure they're calling
the Ants' biological weapons
to justify the assault.
If I'm captured,
they'll force me to confess
and use it as cover
while they throw me in prison for life.
That, or they'll execute me
so I can't talk.
[groans]
[Shaiapouf] Now the smoke user's
out of commission.
the King will only find me a nuisance.
Beelzebub!
the smallest being nano-sized particles.
He can divide himself
into a variety of sizes,
and the smaller they are,
the greater in number they can be.
However, no matter
the size of his clones,
[Shaiapouf] Oh, smoke man,
if you hadn't removed the barrier,
my main body would never
have been able to escape,
and my combat capacity
would have been reduced by half.
I'm sure a puppet master
such as yourself is acutely aware
of the incomparable
difference in strength
between a clone and your own body.
You've already lost.
You should have deliberated
a little more carefully.
When you realized
the pupa was empty,
you could have asked yourself
whether its contents
had escaped the smoke
or whether they remained inside.
for quite a long time,
and some might have been fooled,
but as long as a few
were as skilled as you seem to be,
they would have realized
that I was a fake,
sooner or later, anyway.
and would have searched for me.
And in that case,
I would have had no way to fight you,
given my reduced state of being.
[squish]
In other words,
if you'd kept me imprisoned
as per your initial plan,
you might have lost
some colleagues,
but you would have
been able to defeat me.
Truth be told, I was 10% resigned
to that outcome.
Your emotions were perfectly aligned
to accomplish that.
[sighs] Such a pity.
He then faced Pouf in a battle of wits
and it was certainly more than
a simple product of coincidence.
It would be safe to say Morel's
vast wealth of experience
played a role in saving him.
Not long after entering the palace,
Morel immediately began to prepare
by weighing the strength of the enemies
against that of his own team.
Deep down, he knew
they had underestimated
the power of those
they would be fighting.
[Menthuthuyoupi] The real one's
hidden among the fakes,
trying to attack me, right?
This time, I'm gonna land
a counterpunch on him.
[Morel] Seventy-five left. Seventy-two…
down to seventy.
[dramatic music playing]
and there's a boy close by
who's likely an enemy.
Three more are near
the underground shelter,
Hina, a Soldier Ant, and Bizeff!
They may be heading underground.
Welfin is behind them.
He appears to be in pursuit.
I see.
The girl was injured by a dragon arrow.
Why doesn't the enemy
take this chance to attack Pitou?
Could he know the girl?
East tower antechamber.
[gasps] This area is
simply crawling with enemies.
One, two, three…
[gasps] But Youpi is taking
them out quickly.
It's the smoke guy and a bunch of thugs.
And there's a weird
pointy-headed fat thing.
Not sure if it's friend or foe.
It should take Youpi less than
a minute to find the real one.
[gasps]
The King is gone.
[Menthuthuyoupi chuckles] What's wrong?
You're running out of clones.
Is that it?
Should I give him an opening?
If I do, it'll make it easier
for him to hit me.
Be careful now.
Make it look natural.
Here you go.
Come on!
You bastard.
[Morel] Do you finally get it, sucker?
See, there never was
a real one in the first place.
[Menthuthuyoupi] I'll kill you!
[intense music playing]
Yeah, no kidding, dumbass!
[Shaiapouf] An aura explosion from Youpi?
Did he really need to use
such an ability?
But even so, locating the King
is my top priority.
[Knuckle] Thanks, boss.
If you hadn't set that condition,
I would have snapped and charged him.
It's a good thing you did.
[Morel] Listen up.
The only time I'll make
those pissed-lookin' clones of you
is when you've flown off the handle
and stopped paying attention to anything.
When you see 'em, blend in
with the clones best you can.
Just take a breather,
and refocus on your goal.
Yeah, I get it.
That's enough with the lecture.
After cooling down
and thinking about it,
there's no way that Youpi
would have taken Shoot.
But if Shoot couldn't move around
on his own, then who did?
[growls] Stop overthinking.
I need to focus
on the opponent in front of me!
That was…
-[Bizeff groans]
-[Hina wails]
Hey, hurry up, and get in
before the entrance is blocked up!
[Welfin] Damn it! Bizeff is mine.
If I knew what abilities they had,
I could make a move.
[gasps]
[scoffs]
[singer singing in Japanese]